<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiking on </title>
    <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hiking on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hiking — Overview</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/overview/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s no place quite like the mountains. Welcome! # Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find a compilation of hikes from in and around Switzerland. We&amp;rsquo;ve done our best to include details such as:
Distance and approximate walking times Difficulty rating Photos Maps A Word of Caution # Keep in mind that in case you choose to undertake any of the hikes listed on this website, you do so at your own risk.1 While hiking is generally regarded as a laid back and relaxing sport, severe injury or even death are never out of the question when navigating in the mountains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenatschhütte SAC</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/jenatschhuette_sac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/jenatschhuette_sac/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3+ Number of Days 2 ⇄ Total Distance 25.7 km ↑ Up 1910 m ↓ Down 1910 m Notable Locations Julierpass, Corn Alv, Fuorcla d&amp;rsquo;Agnel, Jenatschhütte SAC, Fuorcla da Flix, Tschima da Flix (Westgipfel) Public Transit Access? Yes Quick Summary # A 2 day hike in central Graubünden near the Julierpass. Tour was accessible via public transit, but we opted to go with the car instead. Parked at the Julierpass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tierberglihütte SAC</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/tierberglihuette_sac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/tierberglihuette_sac/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T4 &amp;amp; K4 ⇄ Distance 5.45 km ↑ Up 670 m ↓ Down 670 m Notable Locations Umpol, Tierbergli Via Ferrata, Tierberglihütte SAC Public Transit Access? No One of the overhanging sections on the Tierbergli Via Ferrata. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # A via ferrata and alpine hiking path near the Sustenpass. There was no public transit available to get to the starting location. We saw one group that hired an alp taxi to pick them up at the Umpol parking lot, so there may be an option to charter a ride from one of the nearby villages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wasserbergfirst</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/wasserbergfirst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/wasserbergfirst/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3+ ⇄ Distance 13.0 km ↑ Up 1200 m ↓ Down 1200 m Notable Locations Liplisbüel/Lipplisbüöl, Wasserbergfirst, Träsmerenseeli, Grossen Träsmeren Public Transit Access? No Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # Parked in one of the parking lots close to the Schwyz/Uri border near Liplisbüel. This hike was very steep (around 1100m of elevation gain over ~4km). The final portion close to the summit of the Wasserbergfirst was partially secured by chains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windgällenhütte AACZ</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/windgaellenhuette_aacz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/windgaellenhuette_aacz/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T2 Number of Days 2 ⇄ Total Distance 18.9 km ↑ Up 890 m ↓ Down 1250 m Public Transit Access? Yes The spectacular views at the end of the Maderanertal looking towards the Hüfihütte SAC. Quick Summary # 2-day hike in the Maderanertal at the Windgällenhütte AACZ. Excellent public transit access. Took the bus from Erstfeld to Golzern, Talstation Seilbahn. Returned via the same bus connection. There were many waterfalls along the length of the valley which, combined with the abundance of lush vegetation, made for some great views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilatus Westgrat</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/pilatus_westgrat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/pilatus_westgrat/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T4 ⇄ Distance 15.0 km ↑ Up 1680 m ↓ Down 630 m Notable Locations Gfellen, Blaue Tosse, Stäfeliflue, Tripolihütte, Mittaggüpfi, Rottosse, Widderfeld, Tomlishorn, Pilatus Public Transit Access? Yes The exposed ridge that led from the base of the Widderfeld (not in view) to the Tomlishorn (peak on the right). Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # A scenic but very exposed hike along the entire western ridge of the Pilatus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bleikigrat</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/bleikigrat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/bleikigrat/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3+ ⇄ Distance 7.6 km ↑ Up 870 m ↓ Down 260 m Notable Locations Niederrickenbach, Buochserhorn, Bleikigrat, Musenalp Public Transit Access? Yes A view of the Buochserhorn from the Bleikigrat. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # A relatively short hike with a few short scrambles over the Bleikigrat. Drove to Dallenwil. Took the cable from Dallenwil to Niederrickenbach. Returned via the cable car from Musenalp to Niederrickenbach and then Niederrickenbach to Dallenwil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnipen-Wildspitz</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/gnipen-wildspitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/gnipen-wildspitz/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3 ⇄ Distance 15.2 km ↑ Up 1100 m ↓ Down 1000 m Notable Locations Goldau, Gnipen, Wildspitz, Steinerberg Public Transit Access? Yes Ascending up the Goldauer Bergsturz to the Gnipen. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # Spring hike to the Gnipen up the Goldauer Bergsturz. Excellent public transit access. Took a train to Arth-Goldau. Returned from the train station in Steinerberg. Ascended via the scarp from a large slope failure that happened in the 19th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jöriseen</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/joeriseen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/joeriseen/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3 ⇄ Distance 11.0 km ↑ Up 760 m ↓ Down 760 m Notable Locations Flüelapass, Winterlücke, Jöriseen, Jöriflüelafurgga Public Transit Access? Yes Looking back towards the aptly named Winterlücke. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # An autumn hike near the Flüelapass to the Jöriseen. We parked near the bus stop Wägerhus/Abzw. Jöriseen. Hiked the loop counter-clockwise. First hiked to the Winterlücke and then later up to the Jöriflüelafurgga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munt Baselgia</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/munt_baselgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/munt_baselgia/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3 ⇄ Distance 15.8 km ↑ Up 740 m ↓ Down 1570 m Notable Locations Zernez, Munt Baselgia, Spi da Baselgia, Swiss National Park, Macun Seen, Lavin Public Transit Access? Yes1 The ridge traverse from the Spi da Baselgia shortly before entering the Swiss national park. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # Hike in the upper Engadin from Zernez to Lavin. We took the Macun Shuttle part way up Munt Baselgia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
