<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiking on </title>
    <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hiking on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hiking — Overview</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/overview/</guid>
      <description>Descent from the summit of the Üssers Barrhorn — one of our all-time favourite hikes. Welcome! # Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find a compilation of hikes from in and around Switzerland. We&amp;rsquo;ve done our best to include details such as:
 Distance and approximate walking times Difficulty rating Photos Maps  A Word of Caution # Keep in mind that in case you choose to undertake any of the hikes listed on this website, you do so at your own risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piz Terza</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/piz_terza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/piz_terza/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T2     ⇄ Distance 15.9 km   ↑ Up 940 m   ↓ Down 940 m   Notable Locations Lü (Val Müstair), Piz Terza   Public Transit Access? Yes     Arrival in Lü # We arrived in Lü from Sta. Maria by car (about a 10-15 minute drive) and parked in the relatively large parking lot at the edge of town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piz Chavalatsch</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/piz_chavalatsch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/piz_chavalatsch/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3     ⇄ Distance 13.8 km   ↑ Up 1200 m   ↓ Down 1200 m   Notable Locations Piz Chavalatasch, Stelvio National Park, Sta. Maria (Val Müstair)   Public Transit Access? No     Arrival # We stayed in the Hotel Alpina in the village of Sta. Maria having arrived the evening before. The drive to the starting point of this hike only took around 10 minutes from Sta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chamerstock</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/chamerstock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/chamerstock/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3     ⇄ Distance 16.3 km   ↑ Up 750 m   ↓ Down 700 m   Notable Locations Klausenpass, Clariden Glacier, Fisetengrat, Chamerstock, Urnerboden   Public Transit Access? No    A chilly autumn hike near the Klausenpass. Arrival # We arrived at the top of the Klausenpass just as the sun was coming up. The weather forecast was absolutely spot-on: the clouds were just under the elevation of the pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guferjoch</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/guferjoch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/guferjoch/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T4+     ⇄ Distance 11.9 km   ↑ Up 1180 m   ↓ Down 1180 m   Notable Locations Sustlihütte SAC, Guferjoch, Sustenlochfirn, Sustenpass   Public Transit Access? Yes    An incredible hike near the Sustenpass on the border between Bern and Uri. Arrival # We parked near the Sustenbrüggli restaurant (there&amp;rsquo;s a decently sized parking lot there).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schwalmis</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/schwalmis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/schwalmis/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3+     ⇄ Distance 11.8 km   ↑ Up 880 m   ↓ Down 880 m   Notable Locations Schwalmis, Risetenstock   Public Transit Access? Yes    A view from the starting point (Gitschenen) up the valley towards the Brisen (peak on the right). Arrival # The starting point of the hike is reached via cable car in St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidelhorn</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/sidelhorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/sidelhorn/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3     ⇄ Distance 7.7 km   ↑ Up 700 m   ↓ Down 700 m   Notable Locations Grimselpass, Sidelhorn   Public Transit Access? Yes   Map Download PDF, GPX     -- Quick Summary #  A very foggy hike from the Grimselpass to the Sidelhorn. There is a PostAuto that fairly regularly goes up to the top of the Grimselpass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kröntenhütte SAC</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/kroentenhuette_sac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/kroentenhuette_sac/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T2     ⇄ Distance 9.4 km   ↑ Up 1060 m   ↓ Down 1060 m   Notable Locations Erstfeldertal, Kröntenhütte SAC   Public Transit Access? No1     -- Quick Summary #  A very warm hike to the Kröntenhütte SAC near the city of Erstfeld. Special permit required to drive up the Erstfeldertal; a day permit costs about 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bächlitalhütte SAC</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/baechlitalhuette_sac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/baechlitalhuette_sac/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T2     ⇄ Distance 9.8 km   ↑ Up 610 m   ↓ Down 610 m   Notable Locations Räterichsboden, Bächlitalhütte SAC   Public Transit Access? Yes    The Bächlitalhütte SAC perched at the end of the Bächlisboden glacial floodplain. Quick Summary #  Day hike from the Räterichsbodensee (near the Grimsel Pass) to the Bächlitalhütte SAC The starting point is easily accessible with both car and public transit The ascent and descent take the same path; there is only one officially marked path which leads to the Bächlitalhütte We&amp;rsquo;d suggest doing this hike when the ground is dry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muttseehütte SAC</title>
      <link>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/muttseehuette_sac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pat-marty.github.io/the-local-ibex/docs/hiking/muttseehuette_sac/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3     ⇄ Distance 11.2 km   ↑ Up 730 m   ↓ Down 730 m   Notable Locations Tierfed, Kalktrittli, Muttseehütte SAC, Muttenchopf, Limmerensee   Public Transit Access? No    The Limmerensee as seen from the Muttenchopf. Quick Summary #  Take a (completely over-engineered) cable car from Tierfed to Kalktrittli. From Kalktrittli take the newly constructed path which has been blown out of the side of the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
