<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiking on </title>
    <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hiking on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hiking — Overview</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/overview/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s no place quite like the mountains. Welcome! # Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find a compilation of hikes from in and around Switzerland. We&amp;rsquo;ve done our best to include details such as:
Distance and approximate walking times Difficulty rating Photos Maps A Word of Caution # Keep in mind that in case you choose to undertake any of the hikes listed on this website, you do so at your own risk.1 While hiking is generally regarded as a laid back and relaxing sport, severe injury or even death are never out of the question when navigating in the mountains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnipen-Wildspitz</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/gnipen-wildspitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/gnipen-wildspitz/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3 ⇄ Distance 15.2 km ↑ Up 1100 m ↓ Down 1000 m Notable Locations Goldau, Gnipen, Wildspitz, Steinerberg Public Transit Access? Yes Ascending up the Goldauer Bergsturz to the Gnipen. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # Spring hike to the Gnipen up the Goldauer Bergsturz. Excellent public transit access. Took a train to Arth-Goldau. Returned from the train station in Steinerberg. Ascended via the scarp from a large slope failure that happened in the 19th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jöriseen</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/joeriseen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/joeriseen/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3 ⇄ Distance 11.0 km ↑ Up 760 m ↓ Down 760 m Notable Locations Flüelapass, Winterlücke, Jöriseen, Jöriflüelafurgga Public Transit Access? Yes Looking back towards the aptly named Winterlücke. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # An autumn hike near the Flüelapass to the Jöriseen. We parked near the bus stop Wägerhus/Abzw. Jöriseen. Hiked the loop counter-clockwise. First hiked to the Winterlücke and then later up to the Jöriflüelafurgga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munt Baselgia</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/munt_baselgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/munt_baselgia/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3 ⇄ Distance 15.8 km ↑ Up 740 m ↓ Down 1570 m Notable Locations Zernez, Munt Baselgia, Spi da Baselgia, Swiss National Park, Macun Seen, Lavin Public Transit Access? Yes1 The ridge traverse from the Spi da Baselgia shortly before entering the Swiss national park. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # Hike in the upper Engadin from Zernez to Lavin. We took the Macun Shuttle part way up Munt Baselgia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muotta Radonda</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/muotta_radonda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/muotta_radonda/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T2 ⇄ Distance 13.4 km ↑ Up 640 m ↓ Down 640 m Notable Locations Sils im Engadin, Muotta Radonda Public Transit Access? Yes Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # An autumn hike among the larches in the Engadin about half way between Maloja and Silvaplana. Drove to Sils im Engadin and parked in a small parking lot just off of the main road. There was also a nearby PostAuto stop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muttseehütte SAC</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/muttseehuette_sac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/muttseehuette_sac/</guid>
      <description>The Limmerensee as seen from the Muttenchopf. Summer 2021 # Difficulty T3 ⇄ Distance 11.2 km ↑ Up 730 m ↓ Down 730 m Notable Locations Tierfed, Kalktrittli, Muttseehütte SAC, Muttenchopf, Limmerensee Public Transit Access? No Overview Map Detailed Description Gallery Quick Summary # Took a (completely over-engineered) cable car from Tierfed to Kalktrittli. From Kalktrittli we took the newly constructed path which had been blown out of the side of the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gotthard 5-Seen</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/gotthard_5_seen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/gotthard_5_seen/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T2 ⇄ Distance 10.7 km ↑ Up 480 m ↓ Down 480 m Notable Locations La Claustra Hotel, Lago di Lucendro, Laghi della Valletta, Gatscholalücke, Laghi d&amp;rsquo;Orsirora, Lago d&amp;rsquo;Orsino Public Transit Access? No Hiking through the fog at the second of five lakes. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # A loop hike starting from the Gotthardpass and visiting 5 different lakes along the way. We did the hike clockwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rothornhütte SAC</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/rothornhuette_sac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/rothornhuette_sac/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3+ Number of Days 2 ⇄ Total Distance 23.6 km ↑ Up 2230 m ↓ Down 2230 m Notable Locations Zermatt, Wisshorn, Rothornhütte SAC, Berggasthaus Trift Public Transit Access? Yes A quiet but strenuous 2 day hike near Zermatt with consistent views of the Matterhorn. Quick Summary # A very scenic but quite physically demanding hike to a lesser-known SAC hut near one of Switzerland&amp;rsquo;s most iconic landmarks. Took the train to/from Zermatt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaiserstuel</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/chaiserstuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/chaiserstuel/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T3+ ⇄ Distance 11.1 km ↑ Up 800 m ↓ Down 720 m Notable Locations Oberrickenbach, Chaiserstuel Public Transit Access? Yes The view from the top of the Chaiserstuel looking towards the Bietstöck. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # A nice hike across many meadows in Nidwalden. Drove to Fell near Oberrickenbach. Took two very small cable cars (so-called Buiräbähnli) up to the starting point. The first was Luftseilbahn Fell-Spis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemsfairenstock</title>
      <link>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/gemsfairenstock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thelocalibex.com/docs/hiking/gemsfairenstock/</guid>
      <description>Difficulty T4 ⇄ Distance 9.0 km ↑ Up 890 m ↓ Down 890 m Notable Locations Urnderboden, Fisetenpass, Rund Loch, Gemsfairenjoch, Gemsfairenstock Public Transit Access? No An incredible panorama view of the Glarner Alps. Overview Map Gallery Quick Summary # Parked at the cable car in Urnerboden. Took the first cable car up to the Fisetenpass. From the Fisetenpass, we followed the alpine trail (white-blue-white) up to the Rund Loch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
